<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BTA</string>
    <string name="exp_nyatapola">Nyatapola Temple is a 5-Roof. Meaning is Five Storeys Roofed Temple. Pagoda Style temple located in Bhaktapur, Nepal.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details">DetailsActivity</string>
    <string name="banner_text">Bhaktapur welcomes you all</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>

    <string name="title_activity_splashscreen">SplashscreenActivity</string>
    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="dattatraya">Dattatreya, Dattā or Dattaguru or Duttatreya, is a God and paradigmatic Sannyasi (monk) and one of the lords of Yoga in Hinduism. In many regions of India and Nepal, he is considered a deity.</string>
    <string name="pottery">Hidden down shop-lined alleyways leading south from the curving road to Taumadhi Tole, Potters’ Sq is exactly what you would expect – a public square full of potter\'s wheels and rows of clay pots drying in the sun.</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_findus">Map</string>
    <string name="blood_and_humiliation">Blood and Humiliation</string>
    <string name="blockade">Blockade</string>
    <string name="brotherhood">Brotherhood</string>
    <string name="_3_kings">3 Kings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_detail">DetailActivity</string>
    <string name="dattatraya_title">Dattatraya</string>
    <string name="nyatapola_title">Nyatapola</string>
    <string name="pottery_title">Pottery Square</string>
    <string name="durbar_title">Durbar Square</string>

    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="appname">Khwopa Assist</string>
    <string name="title_activity_guides">GuidesActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_detail_guide">DetailGuideActivity</string>
    <string name="nyatapola_location_details1">You should be able to see the sky-high rooftop of the Nyatapola Temple long before you reach Taumadhi Tole. With five storeys towering 30m above the square, this is the tallest temple in all of Nepal and one of the tallest buildings in the Kathmandu Valley. This perfectly proportioned temple was built in 1702 during the reign of King Bhupatindra Malla, and the construction was so sturdy that the 1934 and 2015 earthquakes caused only minor damage.The temple is reached by a stairway flanked by stone figures of the temple guardians. At the bottom are the legendary Rajput wrestlers Jayamel and Phattu, depicted kneeling with hefty maces. Subsequent levels are guarded by elephants with floral saddles, lions adorned with bells, beaked griffons with rams’ horns and finally two goddesses – Baghini and Singhini. Each figure is said to be 10 times as strong as the figure on the level below.
    </string>
    <string name="nyatapola_details2">
            The temple is dedicated to Siddhi Lakshmi, a bloodthirsty incarnation of the goddess Durga (Parvati). The idol of the goddess is so fearsome that only the temple’s priests are allowed to enter the inner sanctum, but less brutal incarnations of the goddess appear on the torana above the door, beneath a canopy of braided snakes, and also on the temple’s 180 carved roof struts. In a classic piece of religious crossover, the Buddhist eight lucky signs are carved beside the temple doorways.
            Look for the chariot runners piled up on the north side of the temple.
    </string>
    <string name="wiki_link">See more.</string>
    <string name="dattatraya_location_detail1">At the east end of Tachupal Tole, the eye-catching Dattatreya Temple was originally built in 1427, supposedly using the timber from a single tree. The slightly mismatched front porch was added later. The temple is dedicated to Dattatreya, a curious hybrid deity, blending elements of Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva. Judging from the Garuda statue and the conch and chakra disc mounted on pillars supported by stone turtles in front of the temple, Vishnu seems to have come out on top.</string>
    <string name="dattatraya_detail2">The three-storey temple is raised above the ground on a brick and terracotta base, which is carved with erotic scenes, including unexpected humour where one bored-looking woman multitasks by washing her hair while being pleasured by her husband. The main steps to the temple are guarded by statues of the same two Malla wrestlers who watch over the first plinth of the Nyatapola Temple.</string>
    <string name="pottery_location_detail1">Hidden down shop-lined alleyways leading south from the curving road to Taumadhi Tole, Potters’ Sq is exactly what you would expect – a public square full of potter\'s wheels and rows of clay pots drying in the sun. Nearby buildings were damaged by the 2015 earthquake, but life – and pottery – in the square continues.</string>
    <string name="pottery_detail2">This is the centre of Bhaktapur’s ceramic industry, and it’s a fascinating place to wander around. Several shops sell the finished article, and you can see the firing process at the back of the square, which is lined with mud-covered straw kilns. On the northern side of the square a small hillock is topped by a shady pipal tree and a Ganesh shrine, surrounded by piles of straw for the pottery kilns. In the square itself is a solid-brick Vishnu Temple, which was constructed from remnants of temples destroyed in the 1934 quake, and the double-roofed Jeth Ganesh Temple, whose priest is chosen from the Kumal (potters’) caste. During the harvest in October, every square inch that is not covered by pots is covered by drying rice.</string>
    <string name="durbar_location_detail1">Bhaktapur Durbar Square is the plaza in front of the royal palace of the old Bhaktapur Kingdom and is one of three Durbar Squares in the Kathmandu Valley in Nepal, all of which are UNESCO World Heritage Sites. While the complex consists of at least four distinct squares (Durbar Square, Taumadhi Square, Dattatreya Square and Pottery Square), the whole area is informally known as the Bhakapur Durbar Square and is a highly visited site in the Kathmandu Valley. </string>
    <string name="durbar_detail2">ItineraryThis is a typical itinerary for this productStop At: Bhaktapur Durbar Square, Bhaktapur, Kathmandu Valley, Bagmati Zone, Central RegionBhaktapur Durbar Square, is the royal palace of the old Bhaktapur Kingdom, 1,400 metres above sea level. It is a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The Bhaktapur Durbar Square is located in the current town of Bhaktapur, also known as Khwopa, which lies 13 km east of Kathmandu.</string>
    <string name="ghintangisi_title">Ghintangisi (Gaijatra)</string>
    <string name="tahamacha_title">Tahamacha (Sa:paru)</string>
    <string name="yomaripunhi_title">Yomari Punhi (Dhanya Punhi)</string>
    <string name="gathamuga_title">Gathamuga Chare</string>
    <string name="biskajatra_title">Biska Jatra (Nepali New Year)</string>
    <string name="pulukisi_title">Pulu Kisi (Yenya Punhi)</string>
    <string name="Ghintangisi_detail">Gaijatra is the festival of cows, is celebrated all over Nepal which is locally called as “saparu ” festivial. It is mainly celebrated in Kathmandu valley mainly by Newar community, though other communities also participate in the processions. People take out a rally, in memory of their deceased loved ones, dressed like a cow among many other kinds of strange and humorous costumes with peculiar appearance The festival commemorates the death of people during the year. During the festival, cows are marched in the streets and generally celebrated in the Nepalese month of Bhadra (August–September). It falls on the 1st day of the dark fortnight of Gunla according to the lunar Nepal Era calendar.</string>
    <string name="ghintangisi_detail2">The festivals origins date back to King Pratap Malla’s reign 1641 – 1664 when his son died. The kings wife was so depressed and sad . so this festival is being started by malla king to make her wife to come out of grief and be happy. At that time it is said that the king offered a reward to anyone how could make his wife laugh again. so, from that time , People take out a rally, in memory of their deceased loved ones, dressed like a cow among many other kinds of strange and humorous costumes with peculiar appearance. In Bhaktapur the cow festival is being celebrated differently than all other city among the newar community. Cows are made as tall bamboo poles topped with horns, and the tie with the clothes . These cows are especillay called as “tahamacha” or “tahacha” in local language. Beside that the real cows as well as the statue of cow and the representation of the cow are made from the people . These holy cow are then carried around the street in the memory of the dead relatives. The bhaktapur’s narrow streets make Gai Jatra there a lot of fun.This cow procession go in a clockwise rotation from the streets off Durbar Square down through Dattatreya Square and then up to Taumadhi Square. All the while other processions form every tole join up in the side streets. The bereaved families along with bystanders offer fruits, bread, beaten rice, curd, money among other items to those participating in the procession. Actual cows are also brought out in the rally as it is believed that cows help the deceased to make their way safely to heaven. During the procession the special music is popular and is sang all over the day . the music or song is as ” taha macha gana te , khusing chuike chwe …. ” .</string>
    <string name="tahamacha_detail">The traditional festival of Gaijatra or the ‘cow festival’ that continues for a week in Bhaktapur district started last night from Talejusthan after making Tahamacha and encircling the major part of Bhaktapur Durbar Square. The Gaijatra has started from early morning today to commemorate the demise of 234 from Newar community in Bhaktapur. During this time-honored tradition, people of all ages in the guise of cows and lunatics go around the city, wearing odd costumes in memory of those who died during the past year. The bereaved families offer fruits, bread, beaten rice, curd and money to those participating in the procession including the cows. It is believed that the festival derives its name from the religious belief that the deceased, during their journey to heaven, crosses a legendary river by grabbing the tail of a cow. The Gaijatra observed in Bhaktapur is considered more special, entertaining and satiric compared to other cities.</string>
    <string name="gathamuga_detail1">The early settlers of Kathmandu Valley probably chose to stay back here because of its great agricultural potential, the valley floor having been enriched by the waters of a pristine lake that existed above it for thousands of years before it slowly drained out. In due course, when the settlement developed into a complex society, a distinct culture evolved, giving rise to many traditions and rituals that revolved around the agrarian lifestyle of the populace. The tradition of Gathamuga is one such practice that has survived the passage of countless centuries.</string>
    <string name="gathamuga_detail2">The story starts with the beginning of the plantation season at the onset of the monsoon in July. The combination of an abundance of highly arable land and environmental conditions conducive to farming ensured that agriculture prospered in Nepal Mandala since ancient times. The valley dwellers however, constantly faced a shortage of farm hands. The working-age headcount of the valley population simply was not large enough to take on the vast farmlands available that had to be tilled, watered, sowed, weeded and looked after – all within a short span of about a month during the peak of the monsoon. Scarcity of food, and possible famine was a certainty a few months down the road if the plantation did not go well. The shortage was so severe that even if a death occurred in the family during plantation season, the dead body would be stored in a dark corner in the ground floor until the family could take time out from their farming duties to carry out the funeral rites. To address this labor shortage, at the beginning of the plantation season, the farmers invoked onto themselves, with tantric ceremonies, supernatural spirits who gave them superhuman physical strength and thus enabled them to toil hard in their rice fields day in and day out until the plantation work was over. This practice apparently addressed the labor shortage issue quite adequately. However, the next problem that arose was getting rid of the spirits after they had fulfilled their role of lending extra muscle power to the farm hand. On the fourth day of the waning moon of the month of Shrawan (mid-August), a colorful festival is celebrated in a mirthful atmosphere to bid farewell to these helpful spirits until their contribution is sought again a year later. This festival is known as Gathamuga.</string>
    <string name="gathamuga_detail3">Muga is a Nepal Bhasa (Newa) word for street intersection. A tall dummy made of the common Narkat plant is erected at intersections on the day, adorned by a colorful but fearsome-looking mask. Every household in the area contributes a small rag doll, representing the unwanted spirits residing in that house, to this formidable effigy. A local vagabond, his body painted in grotesque colors, is assigned the duty of looking after the incongruous statuette all day long. As payment for his work, the ill-fated tramp is fed beaten rice and yogurt to his heart’s content. Passersby and nearby shops give him alms of small change. As dusk falls, the awe-inspiring figurine, now representing a compendium of all undesirable forces residing in the neighborhood, is dragged down unceremoniously to the nearest riverbank, together with the unfortunate bum. Amidst the chaos of the unruly hooting and taunting of onlookers, the panhandler quietly slips away from the raucous mob, happily pocketing the day’s earnings, long before the wild parade reaches the river.To counter the risk of running into unwelcome spirits who prowl every nook and corner of the city on Gathamuga, people wear iron rings on this day, as iron is believed to act as a repellent of evil forces. On this pretext, petty vendors make brisk business several days in advance selling all kinds of metal ornaments. At night, the eldest man of each household performs a tantric ritual of driving three-pronged iron nails onto the main doorways of the house chanting mantras, while family members douse all rooms of the house with thick smoke from white and black mustard seed burnt over coal fire on a small clay pot. While this procedure symbolically depicts driving away any remnants of malicious energy from the house, the mustard smoke doubles up as strong insecticide that undoubtedly helps eliminate unsolicited ticks and pests. Finally, an offering of cooked rice, husk and raw buffalo lungs is placed at the street intersection to appease the departed spirits, acknowledging that their services will be solicited the following year. Once this offering ritual, known as Bou Wayegu in Nepal Bhasa, is completed, the doors are locked up tight, and no one ventures out that night, as it is believed that practitioners of witchcraft are especially active in visiting funeral grounds and other places of worship seeking dark knowledge that night. With the plantation task taken care of, the people could then afford to pay attention to enhancing their quality of life. Gathamuga marks the beginning of the festival season – a plethora of religious and cultural events take place in rapid succession over the next several months, allowing the populace to cherish and further develop a civilization that has fostered in an environment of plentifulness and abundance.</string>
    <string name="biska_detail1"><![CDATA[Bisket Jatra, Bhaktapur\'s weeklong festival marks the ancient solar Nava Barsha (New Year) and is the only festival that does not follow the lunar-based Nepali calendar. The jatra commences after a special Tantric ritual in th Bhairab temple in Taumadhi Tole in Bhaktapur. Bhairav and Bhadrakali are then placed in large chariots (locally known as Rathas) and pulled through crowds of cheering onlookers. During the festival people replay a drama passed on over the centuries. The chariots, pause for a tuge of war between the easterna and western sides of town and then move down a steep road leading to a river, where a 25-m high lingam (vertical pole) is erected. In the evening the following day, the pole is pulled down, again in a tug of war and as the pole crashes as the official new year commences. /> <TextView android:layout_width=]]></string>
    <string name="biska_detail2">As per legendary convictions, Bhairab and Bhadrakali are the celestial male and female types of the atmosphere and the Earth, individually. It is said that the conjugation of the sky and the earth made creation conceivable on our planet. The rain that showers from the sky on earth is viewed as the nurturing component, while the earth is the establishment of creation. The opening in which the Yoshin is raised is the image of the female inventive organ, Guheshwori. presented the act of raising two long banners on wooden posts, outlined after the states of the slaughtered serpents. The long shafts were tended to as Yoshin, more prominent as phallic images among local people today. The standards are otherwise called ‘Bishwo dhoja’ after the ruler. The raising of these banners is watched every year with much eagerness. Vivacious young people endeavor to climb the post, utilizing huge ropes keeping in mind the end goal to get hold of the plants set at its top. Any individual who can do as such, it is accepted, will build his odds of siring a male tyke. The post is situated oppositely to the sky and the earth for 24 hours. The occasion is trailed by a major devour all over Bhaktapur. The beginning of the New Year is a glad minute for all Bhaktapurians. A significant number of them gather on the Yoshin Khel in the early hours of the morning, paying respect and making penances to Bhairab and Bhadrakali up until early afternoon. The sprightly air and the merry occasion imply the appearance of another Bikram year. The Yoshin is brought down at night of the New Year. Tunes are played with woodwinds, drums, cymbals and other melodic instruments, and joined by singing once in a while. After the Yoshin is laid to the ground, individuals meet up to pull the chariots towards Gahiti—one of the toles around the local area.</string>
    <string name="pulukisi_detail1">The son of Lord of Heaven is believed to have been kidnapped by a devil named Maisasur who then tied Indra’s son to a pole and killed him. Indra was shocked to hear of his son’s death and sent an elephant, Pulukisi to find and kill Maisasur. But legend says Pulukisi could never find Maisur right up until now. This jatra is a play on the legend where Pulukisi goes around the town in search of Maisasur.</string>
    <string name="changu_title">Changunarayan</string>
    <string name="changu_detail1">This temple is said to be the oldest Hindu temple still in use in the Kathmandu Valley. Built in the two-tiered pagoda style, the main shrine here is guarded on all sides by pairs of real and mythical beasts – elephants, lions, winged lions and ram-horned griffons – and its roof struts feature some amazingly intricate carvings of Tantric deities. Changu Narayan and its associated buildings were badly affected by the 2015 earthquake however; restoration of the complex is under way.</string>
    <string name="changu_detail2">The statue inside shows Vishnu as Narayan, the creator of all life, but the beautifully decorated metal-plate doors are only opened for rituals and only Hindus may enter. The Garuda figure facing the west door is said to date from the 5th century, and in front of this statue is the oldest stone inscription in the valley, dating from AD 464, which recalls how the king persuaded his mother not to commit sati (ritual suicide) after his father’s death. Two large pillars carry a conch and chakra disc, the traditional symbols of Vishnu. Dotted around the courtyard are a series of extraordinary carvings dating from the Licchavi era, showing Vishnu in his various avatars (incarnations). Vishnu appears in the southwest corner of the compound as Narsingha (his man-lion incarnation), disembowelling a demon with his fingers, and as Vikrantha (Vamana), the six-armed dwarf who transformed himself into a giant capable of crossing the universe in three steps to defeat King Bali (look for his outstretched leg). To the side of these images is a broken slab showing a 10-headed and 10-armed Vishnu, with Ananta reclining on a serpent below. The plaque is divided into three sections – the underworld, the world of man and the heavens. In the northwest corner of the compound is an exquisite 7th-century image of Vishnu astride Garuda, which is illustrated on the Rs 10 banknote. The squat temple in the southeast corner of the complex is dedicated to the Tantric goddess Chhinnamasta, who beheaded herself to feed the bloodthirsty deities Dakini and Varnini. Down the steps leading east from the temple complex are the one-storey Bhimsen Pati, with its stone guardians, and the remains of a Malla-era royal palace.</string>
    <string name="tahamacha_detail1">Tall bamboo poles wrapped in cloth and topped with a horn of straw, and an umbrella are carried around the town in memory of the dead.These tall hand made Tahamachas are then lastly flown aong thr rivers as there is strong belief that this cannot be used to cross the bridges at all.</string>
    <string name="nagarkot_title">Nagarkot</string>
    <string name="pilotbaba_title">Pilot Baba</string>
    <string name="ranikot_title">Ranikot</string>
    <string name="manjushree_title">Maha Majushree</string>
    <string name="ghyampe_title">Ghyampe Dada</string>
    <string name="muhan_title">Muhan Pokhari</string>
    <string name="nagarkot_detail1">Nagarkot has a reputation as the top spot for enjoying Himalayan views from the comfort of your hotel balcony. Just 32km from Kathmandu, the village is packed with hotels lining a ridge, affording one of the broadest possible views of the Himalaya, with eight ranges visible (Annapurna, Manaslu, Ganesh Himal, Langtang, Jugal, Rolwaling, Everest and Numbur). However, timing is everything, as the mountains are notorious for disappearing behind cloudy skies. The best viewing seasons are October to December and March to April, when clear skies are likely.</string>
    <string name="nagarkot_detail2">Nagarkot view tower is one of the most popular tourist destinations in Nagarkot. It is situated around 2100 metres above sea level and can be hiked by physically fit hikers in about one hour. You will have a 360 view of the himalayas one of the broadest views of himalayas along with kathmandu valley, lush greenery of national parks, rolling hills,etc. Lots of people they wake up early and do sunrise hiking to Witness the magnificent sunrise along with the grandeur and magnificence of the himalayas. What makes the sunrise hiking very special is with morning sunrise changing colours of the snow capes himalayas. It’s like fire on ice. Still it is a very scenic walk to the view tower during daytime with the stunning views of the unobstructed landscapes, rolling hills, thick pine forests and charming villages.</string>
    <string name="nagarkot_detail3">Nagarkot Panoramic Hiking Trail is a very refreshing walk with stunning views of the majestic Himalayas. This panoramic Hiking Trail is perfect enough for good 3 to 3.5 hours ideal for everyone from young travellers to family with children as it is pretty easy hike. This hike includes Nagarkot Nature Trail + Tamang Village Walk (starting from kartike village) + Panoramic Hiking Trail with 180 degree views of the stunning landscapes with lush greenery. You will enjoy the time in nature and burn some good calories in this trek. Perfect to enjoy the stunning mountain views in quiet and with fresh mountain air.</string>
    <string name="ranikot_deail1">Ranikot Hiking Resort is one of the scenic natural view places of Bhaktapur district for relaxing, recreation and rejuvenate. It is ideally situated in the south-east of Ranikot Vanjyang, which is 7km away from Suryabinayak Chowk and 17km from International Airport, Kathmandu.</string>
    <string name="ranikot_detail2">Ranikot Hiking and Sightseeing trip is especially designed for the beginning hikers. Ranikot hike commences from Suryabinayak Temple of Bhaktapur district and can be covered within four to five hours of leisurely hike. This trail offers great panoramic view of Himalayas and bird eyes view of the entire Kathmandu Valley as well as the historic sites and renowned temples. In a very short distance one can get a chance to see and differentiate the lifestyle of urban city and rural village. You will definitely relish the pleasant and calm environment of Ranikot.</string>
    <string name="ghyampe_detail1">The green forest and rhododendron around us helped us cherish the hiking moment. The downhill road was tough as there was pine needles and leaves everywhere in the forest. It was difficult to balance our steps, and everyone was relieved when it was over. The more we climbed the more we enjoyed the hike. We could see a large building at the top of the next hill and made our way towards it. The more we climbed up and down the more we got into trouble. It was difficult for us to locate the hiking route in the middle of the jungle. After climbing the third hill we found the road to Ranikot and Pilot Baba Meditation Center. Some of us were ahead while the others were still crawling up. We were tired and thirsty. We rested awhile in the meditation center and took some pictures. We saw the mountain which was renowned for giving the illusion of the Sleeping Buddha; we saw the illusion too.</string>
    <string name="muhan_detail">We spent the next few hours trudging along the dirt paths that wound through the woods, pausing occasionally to admire the sweeping expanse of the Kathmandu skyline, or to munch down some cucumbers and peanuts, coupled with a Carlsberg or a vodka shot (although, let the record show, I did not have any!). While the first few hours were a steady and unrelenting ascent, the trail plateaued to a flat trek under shady trees, on the sun-beaten sand, and through a few small streams. I can’t quite believe I did this without losing it over the formidable drop to the river below. One notable moment was when we came upon a bridge over a river that, because of the rainstorm the night before, was completely filled with water and virtually uncrossable, unless we wanted to drench our shoes and socks in muddy water. While a generally undesirable state of being, this was also unattractive because of the heightened risk of leeches- which were the ultimate stressor of the day for many hikers, including myself! We crossed the bridge rather precariously by climbing on to the thick stone rail one each side and inching across to the other side. In hindsight, I can’t quite believe I did this without losing it over the formidable drop to the river below.</string>
    <string name="pilotbaba_detail">a temple located about six km south of the Bhaktapur Durbar Square. That morning, there had been a heavy downpour, but by the time we reached Suryabinayak Ganesh Temple, the skies had become clear. To get to the ashram, we needed to pass through the jungle behind Suryabinayak Temple. Surprisingly, that trail was shrouded in fog. We trod on. The trail to the ashram is fairly easy. We thoroughly enjoyed ourselves during the morning walk, with cool, fresh air blowing from Sipadol Village on our left. The trail was dotted with babbling brooks, a variety of trees--like needlewood and utis, among others--and even bushes of rhododendron and some medicinal herbs. En route, we also saw village folks busy collecting fodder and goats grazing in the jungle.</string>
    <string name="manjushree_detail1">Everyone seems to know and is able to articulate the fascinating story of how the Kathmandu valley was once a lake where the great and powerful serpents lived. Many of us are also able to take any visitor to the southern end of the valley where a clean cut gorge constantly drains the valley of water at Chobhar. At many temple complexes, pauwa or thanka shops and metal statue stores, just about everybody recognizes the popular and famous icon of Manjushree who is depicted holding up a flaming “sword of wisdom” above the head. From children to grandparents, the story of Manjushree and how he stood at the edge of the lake that we call the Kathmandu valley today. One of the sources many people use to validate the story of the history of the Kathmandu valley is the Swayambhu Purana, according to which the Kathmandu valley was once a lake. Manjushree saw a lotus flower in the middle of the lake, decided to cut a gorge at Chobar to allow the lake to drain and the place where the lotus flower settled is the site of the Swayambhu stupa. The valley then became habitable. It is believed that the first human settlement in the Kathmandu valley was named Manjupattan.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_info">InfoActivity</string>
    <string name="tab_text_1">Tab 1</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">Tab 2</string>
    <string name="service_text">Services</string>

    <string name="title_activity_gallery">GalleryActivity</string>
    <string name="yomari_title">Yomari</string>
    <string name="dhau_title">Juju Dhau</string>
    <string name="samebaji_title">Newari Samebaji</string>
    <string name="swo_puka_title">Swoo Puka</string>
    <string name="choila_title">Choyela</string>
    <string name="kachila_title">Kachila</string>
    <string name="nyakhwa_title">Nyakhwa</string>
    <string name="takha_title">Takhaa</string>
    <string name="bara_title">Bara</string>
    <string name="chatamari_title">Chatamari</string>
    <string name="sailesh_desc">Hi, I\'m Sailesh! I really love traveling and tourism industry. I have graduated in travel and tourism management and at the moment I organize tours, treks and other activities. I have experience of 3 years in this field.</string>
    =======
    >>>>>>> parent of 50d8b51... Sets guides and corrects Taumadhi Square
</resources>
